Keith Lewis

SUMMARY

A self-taught Software Engineer with a varied experience whose programming languages include JavaScript, C#, Python, VBA, SQL (PL/SQL, T-SQL, Jet-SQL). Experience with technologies such as Razor, Blazor, .NET Core, .NET, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET, .NET Framework, REST, JSON, SOAP, Azure/AWS, CSS, HTML, Server 2003/2012, SQL Server 2005/2008 R2/2012. IIS 6/8, Oracle SQL, Access, Salesforce and unique experience with platforms such as Splunk.

EXPERIENCE

Momentum 3- Sr. Software Engineer

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

- Work on client projects in PHP and .NET
- Modify existing code to componentize and ensure reusability

CoreLogic, Inc - Sr Professional, Software Engineer

July 2022 – Nov 2022

- Extend internal CRM application
- Modify Stored Procedures to add additional functionalities
- Rewrite onboarding scripts and processes to make them faster and more friendly
- Assist with hot issues

Trinity Computers (Business Application Development) – *Owner/Lead Solutions Magician*

March 2015 - Present

- Building .NET app to make it easier to find FOSS projects to submit your first PR to.
- CareerTrek Developing .NET Core app to assist job hunters with tracking applications, giving recruiters an easy view, and rating recruiters
- Building deployment strategies on AWS
- Planning .NET Core app that will be a multi-industry modular modern ERP solution

Osage Nation - Freelance - Software Engineer

July 2022 - October 2022

- Assist with developing Blazor Applications
- Assist with Software, API and SDK integrations
- Deliver generic, reusable components that can be developed into a framework

Educational Development Corp - Sr Software Developer

November 2021 – July 2022

- Developed app from base in Blazor
- Resolved bugs and added functionality to ecommerce site
- Working remotely with little supervision
- Managed ORM interactions with Dapper and EF/EF Core
- Coached junior devs in proper software practices
- Assisted Jr devs with problematic issues

TEAMClinics - Sr. NET Developer (Contract)

March 2021 - Nov 2021

- Rebuilding existing PHP site in ASP.NET
- Building new and converting existing functionalities to new site
- Working remotely with little supervision
- Assisting with release workflow of project to maintain smooth transition

150 Fox Run Circle, Jenks, OK 74037

417-429-7601

kclewis0614@gmail.com

LinkedIn

jacrys

Github

jacrys

StackOverflow

jacrys

Twitter

jacrystalach

SKILLS

.NET Framework

C#, Razor, ASP.NET MVC, Blazor, MudBlazor, NopCommerce, ASP.NET AJAX, Syncfusion, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Web API, WebForms, WinForms

Web Development

Bootstrap, REST, SOAP, HTML5, Vue, React, AngularJS, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful WebServices

SQL

TSQL, PLSQL, Postgres, MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Access

Servers

Microsoft SQL Server 2008-2012, SSRS, Postgres, MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Access

Soft Skills

Troubleshooting, Process
Improvement, Leadership
Development, Technical Support,
Management, Lateral Thinking,
Leadership

Hard Skills

Software Development, Process Improvement, Data Analysis

Languages

C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, VBA, Ruby on Rails

Data Formats

XML, JSON

Collaboration Tools

JIRA, Confluence, Github

Summit ESP - Developer III

May 2019 - March 2021

- Refactored Django/Angular app into Flask/Vue, Developed in tandem w/ existing app
- Maintained Diango applications and developed Python scripts to meet demands
- Maintained and created servers, networking stacks and ECS in AWS
- Utilised Travis CI to automate testing/validation
- Helped other devs understand database structure and helped onboard new devs
- Managed Git workflow of several projects

Summit ESP - ERP Admin/Business Reporting

March 2017 - May 2019

- Administered Fishbowl, a custom Java ERP backed by Firebird. Added new users, maintained pricing rules.
- Developed Excel-based ODBC reports for users out of MySQL and Firebird and implemented a self-service reporting tool.
- Developed VBA automation for pulling SCADA data for wells out of a PostgreSQL DB.
- Developed C# programs for data import and export from Fishbowl.
- Developed financial dashboard in Microsoft PowerBI and in QlikView.

Avis Budget Group - Reporting Developer III

October 2014 - March 2017

- Developed e-mail survey invitation scheduling tool in C#, utilising customisable timing w/10% response rate that used JSON config files.
- Developed tracking tools utilising custom branching logic in C#.
- Developed cross-framework websites using modern web methodologies.
- Helped other devs with database structure and more ir devs with difficult issues
- Responsible for Server maintenance and performance

Expedia - Hotel Systems Analyst Lead

July 2010 - October 2014

- Resolved issues with hoteliers' access to internal systems, appearance on partner websites and reservations processing incorrectly.
- Created and modified T-SQL queries to complete the duties at hand.
- Mentored candidates in leading and mentoring with a conversion rate of 5 out of
- Developed an automation system for resolution of failed e-mail/ notifications, saving 40% - 60% in time and about \$35,000 yearly.
- Developed and implemented a system in VBA for assignment of analyst casework.

CERTIFICATIONS

Project+ Certification – Badge ffd7fd21-b0af-4e48-a4a7-17e537b7fc09

Issued 4 Sept 2019

A+ Certification – Badge e75a7734-ecf7-4723-a43b-02ba5706eb08

Issued 26 Feb 2020 - Expires 26 Feb 2023

TALKS

Pi Day: Making a RetroPi from a RaspberryPi-

Showing novices how to build a RetroPi

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RBmAswULRyQ 1 Nov 2018

I want to contribute to OSS but don't know how-

Encouraging contributions to FOSS

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FTM0iwclDqY 1 Nov 2018

How to find issues to contribute to during Hacktoberfest-

Development Tools

WSL, VS Code, Visual Studio 2010+

EDUCATION

Western Governors University

Software Development

Expected Sept 2023

Free Code Camp Computer Software Engineering

December 2017

Missouri Southern State University

Pre-veterinary Medicine

December 2005

Webb City High School Biology

December 2000

Showing a tool to find issues to work on https://youtu.be/3lmtgyuF2mg?t=855 1 Nov 2018

VOLUNTEER

Free Code Camp

November 2017 - Present

 $Developer \hbox{--} I worked on development solutions for non-profit organizations in the course of completing online certifications.$

Code for America

May 2015 - Present

Volunteer Developer - Assisted with project dev for the Tulsa, OK affiliate.